

P.Rajesh

14/. Mariyanayagam mainstreet Perambur Chennai -600011 9710022718 | rajeshp.chennai@gmail.com

Objective

B.Sc. in computer science, holding in the field overall 12 years of experience I am a seasoned 2-year Microsoft Digital Skills Trainer in computer literacy and financial literacy, life skills placement assistance, and 4 years of BFSI Investment Banking Domin & Soft Skills Trainer, 6 years of marketing sales training project leader. My expertise is further solidified by certifications in Microsoft 365 and Power BI, placement support, and employment skills training, particularly B2B and B2C marketing sales.

Experience

SRF FOUNDATION

Mar 2023 - Nov 2024

Microsoft Digital Skills Development Associate

Job Placement Training on Microsoft Digital Skills and Soft Skills Computer literacy and Financial literacy,Life skills placement assistance, Microsoft 365. Power BI, basic SQL query language, employability skills, and employment skills at government soft skills training Final-year college students: B.Com, BBA, and MBA Additionally, we are giving the training of sales and marketing knowledge about the BFSI sector and taking the classes in the college daily. Chennai Total 4 College is giving training for Microsoft modules to around 1200 students. Endorsement: Batch training of 25 members for 2 days of classroom training and on-the-job training CRT trainings After giving the Microsoft training module on a daily basis and taking the regular class in college hours every day, all students are given the assignment. On a monthly basis, we give the online MOC test and testimonial videos and case studies of success stories throughout the feedback session. Based on the assessment, students take the marks given the certification.

Rural shores Training academy

Sep 2018 - Mar 2023

Training Project Team leader

FMGC Product Training for Digital Marketing Travel entire Tamil Nadu District Sales Executive Training Support Client My roles and responsibilities I am handling the Tamil Nadu and Kerala teams, also under Team 50 members. I was aligned with the training for each trainer and any processes about our project. I will update the team on a weekly basis and arrange the call with the team to check with the trainer knowledge and process knowledge assigned to train the trainer classes every month. Google form assessment-based elevates the trainer's knowledge about the product knowledge. Classroom Training for New hiring orientation training and existing employees are given refresher training. Directly visit the field and give the training for trainees. Batch training of 50 members for 20 days of classroom training After giving the on-the-job training, we check the employee's process knowledge about the product knowledge; sometimes we give the virtual mode of training also. Check the employee dress code, demo kits, and product knowledge; give the retraining. Monitored staff performance and provided feedback on areas of improvement. Coached team members on best practices for achieving success in their roles. Owned a CRM platform and built and standardised business reporting for strategic analysis and internal business review. We are personal in remote offices. Bottom-up employees contact the grooming sessions. Weekly or monthly, check the report basis for all retraining employees who do not meet the team target. All over Tamil Nadu, supervisors are trainers and sales executives.

Bank of New York Mellon

Feb 2016 - Aug 2018

Process Training Client representive

Represent Client Process Trainer for BFSI, share marketing, and KYC Checking AML CDD checking Fatca supporting training for mutual funds (SIP-Smart Savings Plan), Demant NEW account opening, maintenance, redemption Payment we are sent to money for the savings account We are booking the age-based fund and static fund, fixed income. Money market fund, target risk investment option, Delivered comprehensive training programs to new employees. Training is responsible for ongoing observations of direct reports, providing guidance, mentoring, and support that focus on the performance improvement of the candidate.

Standard chartered Bank

Feb 2012 - Sep 2015

Senior analyst

Standard Chartered Bank sector working in 4 years as the investment banking Demand Account Opening Kyc Details Check AML checking mutual fund and fixed income and share marketing, working with Singapore, booking the mutual fund trades and Middle East Asia (UAE, Bahrain, Qatar), booking the mutual fund SIP trade, opening deposit accounts, monthly P&L, and accruals entries. Placing an order with Standard Chartered Singapore Custodian for

Purchase/Redemption/Transfers and Switch transactions Opening the Investment Service, a/c for new customers Investment document checking to confirm the correctness of the application is a good order. For subscription trades/redemption trades, deal booking in E-Investments. Checking wire transfer payments to fund for information about the customer KYC details, check our system. Investment banking reconciliation, preparing the monthly end MIS reportand daily intraday reports are also sent to the client.

Education

University of Madras
B.sc.Computer Science
60

2011

Skills

- Microsoft office 365
- Sales and Marketing
- Financial Literacy,
- Computer Literacy

Achievements & Awards

• Training Platforms: - Microsoft 365 and Great Learning, Data Analysis and Visualization with Power BI • Cloud Computing and Microsoft Azure

Interests

Playing chess

Languages

- English
- Tamil